<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bruno Pacheco</title>
    <link>https://brunopacheco1.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Bruno Pacheco</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2019 22:05:30 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://brunopacheco1.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Quarkus, Kotlin and GraalVM</title>
      <link>https://brunopacheco1.github.io/posts/quarkus-kotlin-and-graalvm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2019 22:05:30 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brunopacheco1.github.io/posts/quarkus-kotlin-and-graalvm/</guid>
      <description>After a chat with László, where I&amp;rsquo;ve asked some idea to practice Quarkus and GraalVM, he suggested me to code the classic game Snake (AKA Worms by me :P).
Motivations Why Quarkus? I’ve read an article saying that Quarkus is a great promising solution for Java in the Cloud, as it reduces drastically the application’s footprint and it has an insanely fast startup when running on native code, and here is where GraalVM enters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The First Post</title>
      <link>https://brunopacheco1.github.io/posts/the-first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2019 22:38:36 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brunopacheco1.github.io/posts/the-first-post/</guid>
      <description>This is the first post in my personal blog. XD
Finally! It&amp;rsquo;s been more than 10 years since I started working as a developer and no sharing. I think I am a bit late, but better now than never, right?
So, the idea here is just sharing my experiments with libs, languages, tools, Operating Systems, etc. Summing up, anything I think it may worth to share.
Especial thanks to László for pushing me to do that and showing this great tool, Hugo!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://brunopacheco1.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2019 19:25:02 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brunopacheco1.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m graduated in Computer Science and I have an MBA in Software Engineering from the Federal University of Rio de Janeiro.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been working as a software developer for more than 10 years already, mainly in Agile projects.
Most of my experience is related to Java (Spring and J2E), but I also have professional experience with PHP and JavaScript. Lately, I&amp;rsquo;ve played with R, Scala, Kotlin, Python and a bunch of different tools, in order to catch up with the trends and push myself.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>